VLADISLAV LISIN

+7 (953) 874 27 07 ♦ Novosibirsk, Russia v.lisin1@alumni.nsu.ru ♦ telegram ♦ whatsapp

SUMMARY

Data Scientist with experience in solving various problems in the field of data analysis, with a focus on the fintech direction. I understand the life cycle processes of AI models from the stage of setting the task to implementation in production and monitoring. I was engaged in the development, validation and monitoring of ML models. I have a basic understanding of risk management and risk modeling.

НАВЫКИ

Programming Python (numpy, pandas, scipy, matplotlib), SQL, Git

Machine Learning EDA & Feature Engineering

Classical ML stack

feature selection & hyperparametrs tuning

sklearn, statsmodels, optuna, catboost, lightgbm, xgboost

Maths Probability theority, Statistics, A/B tests

Risk Modeling
PD, LGD, EAD, ΠΒΡ, TTC, PIT
Work' Process
Jira, Confluence, Agile, Excel

Soft skills English (B2), Meeting deadlines, Teamwork

EXPERIENCE

Junior Data Scientist

January 2024 - now

Sber, Model Risk Management

- Validation and monitoring of models for assessing credit risk components
- Development of a pipeline for automatic modeling of white-box models
- Model risk assessment and predictive analytics
- Construction of credit risk models, formation and analysis of samples for modeling
- Conducting calibrations of risk models

Intern Data scientist

June 2023 - January 2024

Sber, Validation Management

- Validation of models for assessing credit risk components
- Monitoring the qualitative and quantitative effectiveness of models
- Developing recommendations for improving the quality of models, data and documentation
- Finding critical areas of model performance, stress testing and assessing model risk
- Alternative modeling

ОБРАЗОВАНИЕ

Master's degree, Faculty of Applied Mathematics and Computer Science

2024 - ...

Novosibirsk State Technical University (NSTU)

AI Systems and Machine Learning

Bachelor's degree, Faculty of Mechanics and Mathematics

2020 - 2024

Novosibirsk State University (NSU)

Mathematics and Computer Science